# Santiago Jara González

I'm a .NET Developer with experience designing and creating business oriented software solutions. I have used a wide array of .NET Technologies from Windows Forms to .NET Core and Blazor. I have used Nest JS, a Node framework, to develop APIs as well. As a full-stack developer I'm comfortable working in both front-end and back-end tasks.

As a complement, I have had experience as DevOps, successfully implementing CI/CD solutions. I also have been using different services from cloud based providers such as AWS or Azure.

I have led back-end development teams implementing agile methodologies along with development architectures such as clean architecture and design approaches as domain driven design.

### **EDUCATION**

Universidad Libre, Systems Engineering Degree

FEB 2016 - NOV 2020

SENA, Software Programming Technical Degree

FEB 2014 - NOV 2015

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Ultracom IT

MAY 2024 - Currently Backend Developer

Remote - Medellín, Colombia

Backend developer in a fintech project. Currently using NodeJS and Microsoft Azure.

# Chamba App

JAN 2022 - Currently

Backend Lead Developer(.NET, Nest JS)

Remote - Denver, Colorado

Chamba is a start-up created to help the latino community in the US find jobs. The current focus is on the food services and events industry.

My role in Chamba is as a back-end lead developer. We started the development of the product from scratch, for that we defined a microservice architecture for the back-end that serves 3 front-end applications (web and mobile).

For the technology pool of the back-end we are using .NET, NestJS and GOlang supported on MongoDB and MySQL as database providers.

The most challenging aspect has not been the development of the different microservices, but the implementation of the infrastructure that supports all, which I also was in charge of.

Cra 111a # 148 - 88 Bogotá D.C (+57) 300 247 6776 sajago99@gmail.com

#### SKILLS AND TOOLS

C#

.NET Framework

.NET Core

ASP.NET MVC

Blazor Web Assembly

HTML5-CSS3-JS

Sass

**JQuery** 

**SQL** Server

MySQL

MongoDB

Domain Driven Design

Git

Azure DevOps

Docker

**AWS** 

Kubernetes

Jenkins X

Terraform

Microservices

Nest JS

### **LANGUAGES**

Spanish - Native

English

The infrastructure is 100% cloud-based in AWS and we decided to implement it with Jenkins X, a kubernetes model with pipeline automation through GitOps that handles all CI/CD.

After the implementation of the infrastructure, the development has been pretty straightforward without major technical challenges.

In addition to my technical responsibilities I'm very involved in the development of the business model and also manage all the developers on the back-end side.

## **Pharmetique Labs**

MAY 2019 - MAR 2022 .NET Developer Bogotá - Colombia

My role in Pharmetique Labs (a company in the pharmaceutical sector) was as the only in-house developer of the IT department.

When I arrived I found a lot of outdated practices and legacy technologies, the pool of applications was divided between ASPX(Web Forms) and some with .NET Framework MVC hosted in IIS, the architecture of the projects left a lot to be desired and additionally there was virtually no version control more than the folders of the projects in a server of the company.

Together with my boss, a new head of IT, we started to define better standards and practices for all the steps of the development cycle. Meaning that when I left we had created a development process that we were proud of, the main items were:

- All the projects were on git repositories on Azure DevOps
- We started to use .NET CORE 3.1 and .NET 5.0 when it was available
- For the front-end we decided to use Blazor WebAssembly, a SPA framework in C#.
  As I was the only developer this decision gave us a lot of agility because it was the same language of the back-end, instead of choosing a JS based framework
- We implemented domain driven design and improved the general architecture of the projects by using interfaces, services, repositories, etc... with dependency injection
- We developed a base library for all the projects with utilities and domain driven design basics as a nuget package hosted in our Azure DevOps
- We changed the way the applications were deployed, by implementing pipelines in Azure DevOps that build docker images of the apps and put the images in an AWS ECR repository, making it very easy to just have a docker-compose with reference to the AWS image for each application in the deployment server which improved the management of the deployed apps.

By the end this was a great first job and I grew a lot as a developer. The most challenging aspect was building the new development process, but as the applications were developed for a lot of different areas each with their own needs, I had to learn a lot about different departments' know-how like human resources, logistics, finances, etc..., which had its own minor challenges. Then there was the fact that as it was my first job there were a lot of challenges on the technical side implementing some features because it was my first time doing them, thankfully I was able to successfully overcome them, here are some of the features that I successfully implemented:

- SAP ERP Connections
- LDAP Connections
- Power Automate Integrations
- Microsoft Graph API Connections
- Documents Generation(Excel, PDF)
- XML Handling
- Microsoft Identity integration for Office 365 log-in